Sponges and the wire tool are tools you use every time you throw as well.
A wire tool is what removes your piece from the bat, or from the wheel, and without the wire tool there is no way to disconnect the clay that adheres to the surface when you're throwing it, from the surface.
So I use, I usually get probably one a month just because, you can see I've had this not too long and it's already starting to kind of warp and I like the new crisp ones.
They're very inexpensive, easy to get.
Sponges are a real personal choice as well.
You've got natural and synthetic.
I usually use pretty small ones unless I'm throwing something really large, and then sometimes I'll even use one, each one in each hand.
Synthetics are just obviously rough.
They seem to last a little better, but I really like the smoothness of the natural sponges, plus this angle I can get, sometimes I'll even cut my sponges actually just to get that edge that I need for certain shapes.
This one I haven't cut and it fits perfectly in my hand.
So this is my favorite choice of sponges.